## **SHAIZ** KUNHIMOHAMMED

Product Designer Toronto, Canada

kshaiz.github.io/portfolio k.shaiz@gmail.com

#### **ABOUT ME**

I have been working as a designer for 10+ years, translating business goals into products that satisfy user needs. An avid learner, I am always seeking out opportunities to learn & contribute towards user-centered product development.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Design - Graphic Design (2008 - 2010) University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia

Bachelor of Design (2003 - 2007)

Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati, India

#### **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

Areas of Interest User Research, Design System, Visual Design, Wireframes,

**Prototypes** 

**Toolsets** Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Adobe XD, Figma, Mogups

Programming Languages HTML, CSS, JS, SCSS, React

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Arcesium**, India (2015 - 2021)

### Manager

TASKS: UX Design, UI Design, Ideation & Prototyping, User Research, Visual Design

- Created the design system at the firm leveraging existing trends to ensure consistency in interactions and layouts across all platform applications.
- Designed applications to cater to different areas of post trade activities.

# **PubMatic**, India (2014 - 2015)

### **UX Designer**

TASKS: UX Design, UI Design, Ideation & Prototyping, User Research, Visual Design

 Worked on revamping the firm's Reporting & Analytics tool (for client facing reports).

# **Mettl**, India (2013 - 2014)

### **UX Designer & Product Associate**

таккs: Product Planning, UX Design, UI Design, User Research, Ideation & Prototyping, Usability Analysis, Visual Design, Animation

 Worked on revamping the firm's Reporting & Analytics tool (for client facing reports).

# **Kwik Kopy**, Australia (2010 - 2013)

### **UI Designer**

TASKS: Product Planning, UX Design, UI Design, User Research, Ideation & Prototyping, Usability Analysis, Visual Design, Animation

- Designed a browser based game targeted at teens (age 14-18 yrs.) to raise awareness about bushfires.
- Helped set-up the digital arm of Kwik Kopy Bondi Junction.

# **CarbonBlack**, Australia (2008 - 2010)

## **UI Designer**

TASKS: : Product Planning, UI Design, Visual Design, Resource Allocation

Assisted in preparing the business case for two new platforms.
Created detailed designs for the development team and also assigned & tracked the tasks for final execution of the platform.